Danny呢?
Where's Danny?
不知道 上飞机后 就再没见过他
I don't know.He disappeared just after we took off.
他在那儿!
Here he is.
好的 今天过得很开心
Right,listen,it's been fun,hasn't it?
我会给你们打电话的 我保证过
All right and I'm going to call you just like I promised I said I would.
你的头怎么样了?
How's your head?
没大碍 我会告诉技术部
That's all right,I'll call engineering.I'll get that soap dispenser...
叫他们把给皂机弄低点 太危险了 可能会弄伤眼睛
moved down a little bit.It's dangerous,could have your eye out.
好了 该走了 亲一个!
Okay,got to go.Big kiss.
很好 走吧!
There it is,go on.
- 看够了没? - 哦 让我有点触景生情
- Finished? - Yeah,just having a flashback.
- Ash 弄辆车来 - 没问题
-Ash,get us a car. - Right.
那就是你消失的原因?
So that's where you disappeared to?
空姐们有点小麻烦 鸡毛蒜皮的小事而已
Well,there's something about trolley dollies.It must be all that makeup.
- 花了3个小时? - 哦 没有
- Three hours? - Oh,no.
后两个小时 我在驾驶飞机
No,the last two,I was flying the plane.
本作品由Norm HALFCD Team倾情奉献\N感谢原作提供资源.仅供学习交流.严禁用于商业行为\N请自觉于下载后24小时内删除!如果喜欢本片,请购买正版!
更多精彩 尽在www.NormTeam.com
压制:鬼谷子  字幕:鬼谷子\NCompression:GV-Sir  Subtitles:GV-Sir
- 环境不错 - 随时可以开始
- Nice place. - Start as you mean to go on.
Mick?
听着 我才不在乎他认识什么大臣
Look I don't care if he does know the Chancellor...
900万的价钱 没的商量 等一下 什么事?
the price is still nine million,non-negotiable.Hold.Yes?
预约名单上有点问题
There seems to be some confusion over the reservation.
- 没有您的名字 - Janet?
- There wasn't one. - Janet?
我今早打电话来确认过了
Well,I called this morning to confirm.
我想 只是出了个小纰漏
I'm sure it was just an oversight.
我们的前台小姐是新手
Our reservations clerk is new.
甚至有时候会忘了让客人刷卡
So new in fact,she forgot to swipe your credit card.
你是...?
And you are?
我是经理
I'm the manager.
- 哦 Nigel 是吧? - 是的
- Yes,Nigel? - Yes.
Nigel 我一会来处理 好吧
Nigel,I will see to it right away.
好的 不过如果我可以先....
Well,if I could just take it--
对不起 是的 我在听
Excuse me.Yes,I'm still here.
好的 价钱还是不变 请您稍等一下
Yes,and the price is still the same.Would you hold please?
很感谢您亲自来处理这件事情 我一会就来
Thank you for dealing with this matter personally,I will get right on it.
好的
Right.
- 打扰了 - 没问题
- Thank you. - No problem.
打起精神 开工了!
Okay,let's do what we do best.
飞天大盗 第2季第1集
S02E01 Gold Mine
恕我直言 你想说的是
Let me get this straight.What you're telling me is...
你打算从我这里拿走10万现金
you're going to take my 100,000 in cash...
去做你那无聊的股票生意
do your little share scam thing...
5天内 能还给我50万 是不是?
then bring me back half a million,in five days,is that right?
绝对没错 不过我们得快点
Guaranteed.But we'll have to be quick.
Crown Offshore一旦察觉到 我们控制了他们的股票
Crown Offshore find out that we've manipulated their stock...
我们就玩完了
we'll be dead in the water.
来吧 想想看 Howard
Come on,think about it,Howard.
起码5倍的利润 没有任何风险和麻烦
A guaranteed minimum return of 500%,no risk,no fuss.
- 好象很不可思议 - 没错!
- It sounds fantastic. - It is.
当你的竞争者发现 你在这上面赚了多少钱
Your competitors will be sick when they find out...
他们一定会被气死的
how much money you've made on the deal.
所以你打算让我加入?
And you're willing to let me in?
第一想到的就是你
First name on my list.
一次就拿回50万?
Half a mil,one hit.
- 没问题了? - 还有一个问题
- No questions asked. - I've got a question.
说吧
Shoot.
我的额头上写着"提款机"三个字吗?
Where on my forehead does it say cash dispenser?
- 这次我就不参与了 - 是吗?
- I'm not with you. - Really?
既然你还不知道出了什么问题 那么 让我来说清楚吧
Let me spell it out for you,as you're clearly not the sharpest tool in the box.
你告诉我有这么一件事
You tell me about this great deal you have.
有内应 获得无风险的利润等等
Guy on the inside,guaranteed returns,blah,blah,blah.
我给你1000块 你还我4000块 那时你也参与了
I give you a grand,you give me four back.You with me so far?
我会觉得这是可信的 所以 现在我拿到了3000块利润
I'll take that as a yes.So now I'm three grand up.
还是得谢谢你的
Thank you very much,by the way.
你少了3000块 但是你希望投入之后能有回报
You're three grand down,but you're hoping that's a good investment.
为什么?因为给了我3000块 就能够让我相信你 给你更多钱
Why?Because giving me three grand should convince me to give you more.
这个就是"引诱"
Let's call it bait.
你还好吗?你看起来有点沮丧 来点喝的?
You all right?You look a bit peaky.Can I get you a drink or something?
不用?好吧
No?So.
然后 我给你一大箱子的钱 当然都是现金
Now I give you a suitcase full of money,cash of course.
毕竟 我可以信任你了 是不是?
After all,I can trust you,can't I?
你曾经帮我赚到过钱
You've already made me money.
只是这次...
Only this time...
你消失了
you disappear.
简单 完美的计划
Simple.Imaginative.
绝对不会出差错
What could go wrong?
好吧 既然你这么说 交易取消
Okay,that's it.Deal's off.
显然你并不信任我
Clear you don't trust me.
那么我们就到此为止吧
I suggest we call it a day.
可是 我的钱已经带来了
But my money's here.
不用了 我已经找到其他感兴趣的人了
No,I'll find someone who appreciates what I'm offering.
我有兴趣 当然有兴趣 拿吧 拿走我的钱
I appreciate it,really I do.Please.Please take my money.
再来一次你那神奇的赚钱术
Do your magic thing one more time.
好吧 听着 你已经拿到3000块了
Okay,look,you're 3,000 to the good.
我们就当什么都没发生过
Let's just leave things as they are.
不 我不同意
No,let's not.
把这个交给警察
Give this to the police.
哦 不!
Oh,no.
这算哪门子的欢迎方式?
What kind of welcome's that?
谁让你们没付清帐单就消失了
The kind you get when you disappear without paying your tab.
还以为 你会很高兴见到我们的
We thought you'd be pleased to see us.
会计认为 没结清欠款前 不做你们的生意为妙
My accountant said I should bar you until you pay up.
- 你请会计了? - 是的
-You've got an accountant? - Yes.
所以 你们都被拒之门外了
So,you're all barred.
好吧 Eddie 如果你想那么做的话
Okay,Eddie,if that's the way you feel about it.
- 来最后一杯 行不行? - 为过去的时光
- How about one last drink? - For old times' sake.
好吧 就一杯!
Okay,one drink.
谢了 Eddie 拿过来吧
Cheers,Eddie,bring them over.
哦 别忘了记在帐上
And put them on our tab.
这里有个抽中乐透奖的
We got a lottery winner here.
如果你想玩1400万:1的游戏
If you beat the odds of fourteen million-to-one...
还是留着你的钱吧
you deserve to keep your money.
通信大亨获得大笔解聘费?
Telecommunications boss gets golden handshake.
抱歉
Sorry.
喂?
Hello?
Alice Alice Alice!
Alice,Alice,Alice!
天 当然 我当然记得你
God,yeah.Yeah,of course I remember.
是的 我也是 都快死了
Yeah,mine is,too,it's killing me.
我现在不能讲电话 宝贝 因为 我正在...
I can't talk right now,sweetheart,'cause I'm,you know,I'm just about to....
剧院正在入场
I'm just about to go into theater.
是的 好的 我会给你回电话的 一定
Yeah,all right,I'll definitely call you back.Definitely.
好的 再见
All right,goodbye.
再见
Bye.
你真是个令人作呕的家伙 Danny
You're a very sick man,Danny.
羡慕我被美女围绕着?
Look at me,surrounded by angels.
好吧 最后一杯 喝完 你们就可以走了
All right,this is your last drink,then you're all barred.
你该改进下服务态度了 Edward
You really should work on your customer service,Edward.
- 真是每况愈下 - 那些付了帐的客人才有好脸色看
- You're almost there. - I save that for paying customers.
我想你们都听说Harry的事了吧
I suppose you've heard about Harry.
- 谁? - Harry Holmes 跟你们一样的 是不是?
- Who? - Harry Holmes,one of your lot,ain't he?
- 老一代的骗术专家 - 是的 他是最厉害的之一
- Old-time grifter. - Yeah,he's one of the best.
怎么会这样 Harry?
What happened,Harry.
好象几年前 他被人骗走了3万
Seems he was taken for 30,000 a few years back.
他记下了手法
He remembered the sequence.
所以 他让你相信他上当了 然后再把你告发了?
So he took you for the convincer,and then turned you in?
- 花了多少钱? - 3000
- How much? - 3,000.
对了 这我就不明白了
This is what I don't get,right.
为什么他不直接拿了这3000块 然后 放你走就是了
Why didn't he just pocket your three grand and,you know,let you walk away?
他喜欢这么干 知道吧
He loved it,you know?
炫耀他自己有多聪明
Telling me how clever he was.
把我们所有的对话都录音 然后全部作为证据
Taped every conversation we had,then made a full statement.
他是谁?
So who is he?
一个年轻的投机者 叫Howard Jennings
A young high flier called Howard Jennings.
他是个地产经济人 他为很多地产商 寻找可供开发的地块
He's a property broker.He finds land for the major developers to build on.
做些污秽不堪的勾当
Nasty piece of work.
我是真的以为 他上当了
I really thought I had him.
他很急进 总是提前一步 获悉所有对手的资料
He's obsessive,always one step ahead,has files on all his opponents.
了解所有的事 不留一丝机会给对手
Checks everything out,nothing left to chance.
上个月 某个竞争公司
A rival company snatched a large parcel of land...
在他的眼皮子底下 弄走了一大块地皮
from under his nose last month.
他用高尔夫球杆砸碎了办公桌
Took a nine iron to his own desk.
看上去 他需要学学如何控制情绪
It's like he needs a course in anger management.
更糟糕的是 他们在挖掘土地的时候 竟然发现了古罗马时期的硬币
Made worse when they discovered a cache of old Roman coins during excavation.
显然 价值连城
Worth a fortune,apparently.
那件事 让他成为了笑柄
Made him a laughingstock.
似乎 好人是不会有这种遭遇的
Sounds like it couldn't happen to a nicer bloke.
- 你还需要点什么? - 不用 谢了 Mickey 不过我很好
- Do you need anything? - No.Thanks,Mickey,but I'm fine.
不过 很高兴你们能来看我 我知道 那样做并不容易
I appreciate you coming,though.Know it couldn't have been easy.
Mick 你在里面的时候 也穿成那样吗?
Mick,did you have to dress like that when you were inside?
- 别提了 Danny - 只是开个玩笑
- Drop it,Danny. - It was a joke.
- 这个玩笑糟透了 - 抱歉 Mick 我无意冒犯
- A bad one. - Sorry,Mick,no offense.
不用穿成那样
None taken.
听着 好吧 大家听好
Listen,right,listen up.
我想 我们来搞定Jennings这个家伙
I say we take this Jennings bloke.
- 我们不行 - 为什么不行?
- We can't. - Why not?
- 告诉他 Ash - 好吧 他知道太多了
- Tell him,Ash. - Well,he's clued up.
当有人发现他们被骗了 他们就会更小心
When some realize they've been conned,they get obsessed by it.
做很多相关的调查
You know,research the subject.
他知道很多 足以迷惑Harry这样的熟手 并且反过来骗得钱财
And if he knows enough to take convincer money off a good grifter like Harry...
正如他所做的
that's what he's done.
也就是说 他不会再次上当
Which means they can't be taken again.
诈骗的首要原则...
First rule of the con...
凡事 都要比人早一步下手
always stay one step ahead of the mark.
等一下
Hang on a minute.
我记得首要原则是 你不能欺骗老实人
I thought the first rule of the con was you can't cheat an honest man.
- 这条也是 - 这也可以吗 Albert?
- It's that,too. - Yeah,can he do that,Albert?
只要他想 他就可以更改首要原则?
Can he just change the first rule when he wants?
当他们知道有人在骗他们 你就不能再去骗他们了
You can't con someone who knows when they're being conned.
你的意思是 这个家伙比我们都聪明?
You're saying,this bloke's too clever for us?
不 我的意思是 我们只打有把握的仗
No,I'm saying we play percentages.
如果 目标知道诈骗的规则 我们就没什么可玩了
And if the mark knows the plays,it leaves us nowhere to go.
抱歉
Excuse me.
天 真讨厌!
No,idiot.
嗨 美女
Hello,gorgeous girl.
是的 和病人在一起 谁?
Yes,I'm with a patient.Who?
是的 我们是在旅途中邂逅的
One of the passengers,that's right.
没错 遇到气流 太恐怖了 象是场噩梦
Yeah,it's the turbulence in the air....Sickness,nightmare.
好的 我会给你打电话的 一定 再见
All right,yeah,I'll call you,of course.Bye.
听着
Look.
难道你们就没其他的 想对我说的?
What's the one thing you've said to me more than anything else?
除了"闭嘴 Danny"
Apart from ''Shut up,Danny.''
听着 每个人都有缺陷 是吧?人人都有弱点的
Listen,now,everyone has a way in,all right,everyone's got a weakness.
也许他就是这个原则的例外
Maybe he's the exception that proves the rule.
也可能不是 对不?
Maybe he's not,okay?
是人就会有缺陷 就会有弱点
A mark is a mark is a mark...
就可以下手
is a mark.
行了 既不需要你用功夫 又不需要什么侦察机
All right,look,there's no point doing all this Kung Fu,Grassyhopper stuff...
Mickey 相信我 你不会想要我去做这个实验吧
Mickey,with me,if you're not going to let me put it to the test.
Danny 诈骗是一门科学
Danny,the long con is a science.
你必须理智 考虑到各种可能性 不能有一丝破绽
It's about reason,covering all the angles,leaving nothing to chance.
是的
Yeah.
可是 这就象是去瓶里拿东西一样轻松
But it's also about having the bottle to go for it.
听着 白痴都可以拿走瓶里的东西
Look any idiot can go for it.
而诈骗专家骗走他们的钱
But a con artist takes the mark's money...
他们并不知道 甚至没发现自己被骗了
and he doesn't even know he's been conned.
是的 好吧 我们也会有直觉吧?
Yeah,okay.But isn't it also about gut instinct?
Albert 你怎么称呼它的?诈骗第六感?
What's Albert call it?What do you call it,Albert?Grift sense?
最重要的是 不要冒任何不必要的风险
Most of all it's about not taking unnecessary risks.
好吧 不问这个 换个人来问
All right.Let's put it out.Let's ask the others.
别问我 我退出
Leave me out of it.
当我不存在 行吗?
Just pretend I'm not here,all right?
多谢 好吧 让Albert来决定
Thanks a lot.Okay.Let's let Albert decide.
好吧 表面上看 毋庸质疑...
Well,on the surface,granted...
企图诈骗Jennings的确不太明智
trying to con Jennings is a bad idea.
但是 也有另一种可能性
But there's another challenge here.
不同风格的诈骗方式
Two styles of grifting.
一种深思熟虑过的 就象Mickey说的 各种因素都得考虑到
One reasoned,well thought out,as Mickey says,covering all the angles.
另一种 更需要直觉...
The other more intuitive...
更危险 需要当事者步步为营
daring,relying on one's ability to think on their feet.
很难说 哪种方法更好
Which is the best?Hard to say.
各自有各自的优点
They each have merits of their own.
瞧 说到关键了
See?I got merits.
当然 真正的实施 需要两种互相配合
Of course,the true con has elements of both.
那就这样做 象Albert说的 那是个挑战
That's it,then,what Albert says.It's a challenge.
什么?
What?
赌一把吧 成功了 就是我赢 没有成功 那么换你来
We take the con.If it works,I win,and if it don't,you do.
- 你不觉得 这样做有点孩子气? - 没有 Mickey 我不觉得 来吧
- You don't think that's a little childish? - No,Mickey.No,I don't.Okay?
50便士
50p?
- 什么? - 50便士 赌我可以搞定他
- What? - 50p says that I can take him.
- 50便士? - 是的 现金
- 50p. - Yeah,cash.
赌我能搞定这个不会上当的家伙
To con the un-connable mark.
当然 Mickey 如果你是个软脚虾
Of course,if you're too much of a girly wuss,Mickey...
你没有胆子打这个赌的话 现在就忘了这个赌约
a little bit too frightened to take the bet,we'll just leave it right there.
好吧 大明星 就和你赌一次
Okay,superstar.You have got yourself a bet.
所以 不管怎样 我们都得下手了?
So we're actually going to do this?
显然是的 没错
Well,it looks like it.Yeah.
告诉他们 不要调解
Tell them it's non-negotiable.
我要那个家伙接受最高刑罚 管它多少年
I want this loser sent down for whatever the maximum sentence is.
是他想玩游戏 他输了 就得付出代价 就是这样
He played the game,he lost.He pays the bill.End of.
很简单 再想想吧
Very simple,just think.
仔细想想
Think it through.
听着 Danny 为什么你总想要单枪匹马?
Look,Danny.Why do you always have to go out on a limb,hey?
我不知道 只是我的内心这么跟我说 Ash 然后....
I don't know.I just hear myself saying it,Ash,and then...
就这样 不管怎么说 我已经开始了
that's it.Anyway,I'm in it now.
需要帮助吗?
Need any help?
不用
Me,no.
不 谢了 我都已经准备好了
No,thanks.No,I've got it all sussed.
我只是...只是在过一遍所有的细节
I'm just really,you know,going through those fine details.
细节?
Details?
我知道你怎么想
I know what you're thinking.
你知道?
Do you?
你在考虑的最重要的事就是...
You're thinking the most important thing...
怎么才能让他不敢报警 是不是?
is to keep him away from the police,right?
大部分受害者都不会报警
Most marks don't report a con...
因为他们认为他们做的事是违法的
because they think they've done something illegal...
更惨的是 有些人不知道什么时候被骗的
or better still,they don't know they've been conned in the first place.
是的 没错
Yeah,that's right.
对于Jennings来说 名誉是至关重要的
With Jennings,his reputation is the biggest thing.
他要自己成为最优秀的
He has to be seen as top dog.
厉害!
Brilliant!
厉害啊 真是....哇!
Brilliant.It is....Wow!
你就象我肚子里的蛔虫
That's like you're in my head.
你大概在想一个办法 如果他报警了的话
You're probably thinking of a way to make him look stupid...
他就会象个傻瓜 是不是?
if he did go to the police,right?
没错
Right.
有些事可能会毁了他的名声 有些特别的事....
Something that might ruin his reputation,that sort of thing?
知道嘛 因为他太聪明 太聪明了
You know what?That is really,really clever.
是啊 有时候我也会害怕这点
Yeah,I scare myself sometimes.
好的 我明白了!各位 听着
Okay,I've got it!Right,listen up.
1个小时后集合 别迟到 谢谢
Briefing back here,one hour.Don't be late.Thank you.
2个小时吧
Let's make it two.
听着 我们得做得夸张点...
You see,whatever we do has to be so outrageous...
这样尽管他知道自己被骗了 也不会去报警
that even if he knows he's being conned,he ain't going to go to the police...
因为他会象个傻瓜 好吧 我从Harry那里获得了灵感
because he's going to look a prat.Right,I got the idea from Harry.
记得嘛 他说Jennings这家伙非常易怒...
You remember he said this Jennings bloke was miffed...
因为另一家公司找到了金币
'cause that other company found all them gold coins.
- 是的 所以? - 所以....所以...
- Yeah,and? - And...
我们可以卖给他一块地
we sell him a piece of land...
我们得让他相信 地底下有东西
but we make him believe there's something under it.
比如?
Such as?
我看过这里的博物馆展览品
I read about this museum exhibition--
- 你读得明白? - 是的 谢谢 Stacie 我识字
- You read something? - Yes,thank you,Stacie.I can read.
多谢!
Thank you.
事实上 是Irish John告诉我的
Actually,Irish John told me about it.
这个 Jubilee展品
Right.The Jubilee collection.
黄金铸品 可以追溯到铜器时代
Gold artifacts dating back to the Bronze Age,found...
是在把Jubilee线扩张到东部的时候发现的
when they were extending the Jubilee line into the East End.
是的 我听说过这个
Yeah,I heard about that.
至今人们还不清楚 这些展品是打哪儿来的
What they couldn't work out was where all the gold came from.
有假设说 拥有大量该物品的
It suggested that the Bronze Age inhabitants...
是铜器时代的土著居民 位置就是..
of what would eventually become London...
- 现在的伦敦 - 多谢了 我正打算说这段
- had a plentiful supply-- - Thank you,I was just about to say that.
等一下 这些东西为什么 不可能从其他地方来
Hold on.Why couldn't the gold have come from somewhere else?
事实上 更象是Mendips或Wales 不过...
There are more likely sites in the Mendips or Wales,but...
鉴于此后5000年还没有发明出M4炸弹 所以很有可能是就地开采到的
as the M4 wasn't built for the next 5,000 years,chances are it was mined locally.
- 找寻金矿 - 好了 多谢了
- Gold mine scam-- - Hello,thank you.
- 这是我的计划 - 等一下
- This is my con. - Wait a sec.
我们打算卖给这家伙一座金矿?在伦敦中部?
We're going to sell this guy a gold mine?In Central London?
为什么不行?
Why not?
这大概是我挣得最轻松的50便士了
This is going to be the easiest 50 pence I've ever earned.
好吧 行了 现在先别花你的钱
Okay,yeah,all right.But don't spend your money just yet...
因为接下来的 才是重点
'cause that is the whole point.
最奇怪的是...
The more outrageous it is,the less...
他会亲眼看着金子的出现
he's going to see it coming.
不过 听上去似乎有悖逻辑
Well,there's a twisted logic in there somewhere.
不 他说的没错 我是说...
No,he's got a point.You know,I mean...
谁会笨到在伦敦的中部去买一座
who'd be stupid enough to try and sell a fake gold mine...
假的金矿?
in the middle of London?
就是这样
There you go.
Harry告诉我 Jennings会看Telegraph杂志
Harry told me Jennings reads The Telegraph.
我们就再弄一份给他
So we mock up a copy for him.
现在他肯定知道这次展览 不过 我们再提醒他一次
Now he must know about the collection,but let's remind him.
下一步 找地皮
Phase two,the land itself.
Ash帮我们找了块地皮
Ash has found us a place.
1.5万平方英尺 距离这些藏品的发现地不到1英里
15,000 square feet,less than a mile from where the artifacts were found.
长年以来一直都是废品回收站 如今...
Run as an old rag and bone yard for years.Now the old guy--
非常感谢 现在老人准备退休了 他很愿意卖给我们
Thank you very much.The old man is retiring,so he's willing to sell it to us.
协议是我们一找到买家就支付费用
The agreement is we pay when we find a buyer.
我准备以双倍的价钱卖给Howard
Okay,I say we sell it to Howard for twice what the land's worth.
我们把老人送去Bognor Regis度假
We'll pack the old boy off on holiday to Bognor Regis...
所以他有两周时间 不会出现
so he's going to be out of our hair for two weeks.
怎么样才能让他相信 那里有黄金?
How do we convince the mark about the gold?
我们要做的就是埋个伏笔
All we got to do is plant the seed.
让他考虑去做个土壤测试
Just enough to get him to take a soil test...
再找一个专家来做评估
and then get a gold expert in for evaluation.
当然 专家也会是我们的人
And he,of course,will be one of us.
你怎么认为?
What do you think?
再多挖几个洞 你可以直接滤茶喝了
If it had any more holes,you could strain tea with it.
老实说吧 伙计 你是怕输了这场赌局
Let's be honest,mate,you're just frightened of losing the bet.
好吧 先做什么?
Okay.So what's first?
- Ash 办公室怎么样了? - 再过几天就弄妥了
- Ash,what about the office? - We'll be set up in a couple of days.
好的 这样 剩下的就是 看我怎么把他弄进来
Right.Then that leaves nothing more than for me to reel him in.
- 什么? - 有问题?
- What? - Problem?
当然 Albert才是下套的人
Yes,Albert's the roper.
这个是分工流程 大家各司其职
That's how this works,we all do our own jobs.
Albert下套 Stacie负责财务...
Albert ropes,Stacie's the banker...
Ash负责提供支援 你和我负责重点
Ash is our fixer,and you and I play the inside.
好吧 无意冒犯你 Albert 可是我们不能太教条主义了
I know that,okay,and no offense,Albert,but we can't do this one by the book.
如果Jennings知道所有步骤 我们就得弄个新的来
If Jennings knows all the moves,we've got to invent new ones.
没有人下套 没有甜头
No roper steering him to the inside man,no convincer.
我准备直接上手
I'm just going to dive straight in.
"嗖――"
Whoosh.
"嗖――"?
Whoosh?
相信我 他不会知道 他失在哪一步的
Trust me,he won't know what's hit him.
你怎么想的?
What do you think?
等待结果出现是种折磨
It's a disaster waiting to happen.
告诉我 我想错了
Tell me I'm wrong.
我不行
I can't.
我想 我们得留意一下他
I think we should keep an eye on him.
好的
All right.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
等一下 我和你一起去
Wait,I'll come with you.
你总是不安于轻松的生活 是不是 Danny?
You don't make life easy for yourself,do you,Danny?
会成功的 Albert 相信我 会成功的
It'll work,Albert,all right.It will work,just trust me on it.
- 一切皆有可能 - 什么 你觉得我好高骛远?
- Anything is possible. - What,you think I'm out of my depth?
用你的天赋让我们大吃一惊
Use that talent of yours and surprise us all.
记住 第一印象是至关重要的
And remember,your first meeting with a mark is crucial.
走错了这一步...
If you get off on the wrong foot...
- 就全功尽弃了 - 没错
- you're beat from the start. - Right.
在你说话之前 cold read他 (cold reading:一种心理术)
Cold read him,learn everything you can...
获得你所要的信息
before you say a word.
冷什么?
Cold what?
你应该知道cold reading
You do know about cold reading?
哦 cold reading 我当然知道cold reading
Oh,cold reading.I know about cold reading.Yeah.
好吧 要不要再复习下?
Well,how about a little refresher course?
如果有时间 我想....当然行
If we've got time,I mean....Yes,please.
事实上这很容易 跟我来
It's really very simple.Follow me.
你看见什么?
What do you see?
好的
Okay,right.
- 一个家伙 - 再具体点
- A bloke. - More specific.
你要让他相信你们俩志趣相投 就象是你们心灵相通
You've got to convince him that you're like-minded,like two peas in a pod...
你可以成为他的朋友 要做到这个 你得知道他到底是谁
that you could be his friend.Now to do that,you need to know who he is.
做一条变色龙
To become a chameleon.
变色龙
Chameleon?
好吧 他的名字...
Okay.His name...
叫mark
is Mark.
好吧 认真点 好的 他....
All right,okay,seriously.Well he's...
- 他离婚了? - 真是不错
- he's divorced? - There you go.
但也许他没离婚
Maybe he's not,though.
他在出差 可以在这里找艳遇
He's on a business trip.Could be here on the pull.
- 没用古龙水 - 好吧
- Not enough cologne. - Okay.
还有什么?
What else?
离异 周末会在快餐店 探望孩子们
Divorced.He sees his children on the weekends,at fast food restaurants.
他得支付抚养费 而这笔费用...
He has to pay a fortune for the maintenance and that's left him...
让他精疲力竭
tired and stressed.
他可能从不在家吃饭
He probably didn't cook before he left home.
因此 最近他体重下降了
Consequently he's lost weight recently.
不行 我做不到
No way.I'm not having that.
看他的袜子 瞧见没 ――有孩子
Look at his socks.See?Children.
还有指甲 ――压力很大
And his nails.See the stress?
他的皮肤...
His skin.
那是快餐 对吧?
That's the fast food,yeah?
这些我都知道了 不过你怎么知道他减肥了?
Okay,I'm having all of this,but how you telling me he's lost weight?
看看他的皮带
Look at his belt.
看这线 都有束痕了
See the line.He's pulled it in a notch.
Mark 你好吗?
Mark,how are you?
你最近是不是减肥了?孩子们怎么样?
Have you lost weight recently?How are your lovely children?
多谢
Thanks.
她还是很喜欢你
She's still got the hots for you.
是吗?
Is that so?
怎么 装作不知道?
What,like you didn't know?
这是我呆过的最棒的团队 我想就这样 永远不改变
This is the best crew I've ever had,and I intend to keep it that way.
你Stacie在一起 就会把它搞砸?
And you think hooking up with Stacie would spoil that?
我知道 我和她在一起会搞砸
I know hooking up with Stacie would spoil that.
也许你该告诉她
Maybe you'd better tell her.
伙计们 凡事都要先下手为强
Guys,it's all about staying one step ahead of the competition.
- 你想要什么 你就... - 去争取它
- You see what you want and you just... - Go for it.
不是"争取" Nick 是"得到"
It's not ''go for it,'' Nick.It's ''get it.''
我就是这个意思
Yes,I mean,that's what I meant.
Islington的那个案子
That site I had in Islington.
有个83岁的老人不肯签约
83-year-old tenant blocking the deal.
她不想搬走 她担心她的小猫
She wouldn't move because she was worried her little cat...
会找不到回家的路
wouldn't find its way home.
你一定大伤脑筋
That's wrinklies for you.
所以 我开车轧死了那只猫 她两星期内就搬走了
So I ran over the cat,she signed within a fortnight.
你要的东西 一定要紧紧攥在手心里
See what you want,grab it by the balls.
去你的吧
Off you go.
来杯香槟 伙计
Glass of shampoo,squire.
哦 天哪!真够养眼的 不是吗?
Oh,God,scenery's nice,isn't it?
没人打算去碰碰运气?
Anyone tried to pull yet?
Nick打算去试试 不过他忍住了
Nick was just about to try his luck,but he bottled it.
我说了 她可能在等人
I told you,she's probably waiting for someone.
好吧 有一种办法可以知道
Well,there is only one way to find out.
50英镑 赌我能钓到她
50 quid says that I pull it.
好啊 赌就赌
Okay,you're on.
- 是嘛? - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
好吧 祝我好运
All right.Wish me luck.
他不行的
Not a chance.
嗨!
Hi.
我有点紧张 不过 别担心 我不是来引诱你的
I'm a bit nervous,listen,don't worry I'm not trying to pull you.
我男朋友会杀了我的 开个玩笑
My boyfriend would kill me.That's a joke.All right.
认真点 今天是我妈妈的生日 我很爱她 我很尊敬她
Seriously,it's my mom's birthday,and I love her,I adore her.
我想 现在我需要的是女士的建议
I suppose what I'm really looking for is a bit of womanly advice.
别伤心
Now,don't cry.
我有个女朋友 我也很爱她 但是她却让我一个人度周末
I had a girlfriend and I loved her but she dumped me on holiday.
那也不要紧
That's all right,thank you.
就我看 他似乎渐入佳境
He seems to be doing all right to me.
你没戏了
Could've been you.
- 50 是不是? - 给钱吧 Nicholas
- Fifty,weren't it? - Pay the man,Nicholas.
知道我怎么想 Nichol-ass?
You know what I always say,Nichol-ass?
你要的东西 一定要紧紧攥在手心里
You see what you want,you grab it by the balls.
请你们大家喝一杯 怎么样?
Tell you what,why don't I buy you all a drink?
不用 谢了
No thanks.
我们得回去了
We have to be getting back.
- Howard? - 我想再呆一会
- Howard? - I think I'll stay for one more.
- 那么一会办公室见 - 好的 一会见
- See you back at the office,then. - Yeah,see you.
我讨厌无能的人 你呢?
I hate a bad loser,don't you?
我也是 Howard Jennings
Absolutely.Howard Jennings.
Paul Carrington
Paul Carrington.
他喜欢这么干 知道吧
He loved it,you know?
炫耀他自己有多聪明
Telling me how clever he was.
把我们所有的对话都录音 然后全部作为证据
Taped every conversation we had,then made a full statement.
我是真的以为 他上当了
I really thought I had him.
我们就当什么都没发生过
Let's just leave things as they are.
不 我不同意
No.Let's not.
你是做什么的?
So,what do you do?
房地产
Property.
- 房地产? - 大部分是地产开发
- Property? - Development,mostly.
我找到土地 老板把它卖给出价最高的人
I find the land,you know,the boss flogs it to the highest bidder.
- 公司的名字叫什么? - Cityrise 听说过吗?
- What's the name of the company? - Cityrise.You heard of it?
- 没有 - 总部在Manchester
- No. - Based in Manchester.
伦敦刚开了个办事处
Just opened a London office.
- 生意怎么样? - 还不错
- And how's business? - It's okay.
那么你在哪里工作?
So who do you work for,then?
我给自己打工
I work for me.
噢 那可是我的梦想
Now that is my dream.
让Golden Balls那老家伙看好自己的生意
Tell old Golden Balls where to stick his job.
Golden Balls?
你很快就会知道他 他打算打败所有的竞争对手
You'll know him soon enough.Going to blow away the competition,he says.
是吗?
Really?
他预计 3年内能成为 伦敦最大的一家地产公司
Biggest in London in three years,he reckons.
那时候 我大概不在了
Anyway,it is time I was off.
这样 Howard
Listen,Howard.
下次再聊怎么样?
Can we do this again?
好吧
Yeah,maybe.
给我的秘书打电话
Give my secretary a call.
真惭愧啊!
Shame.
你明天有安排了吗?
How you fixed for tomorrow?
是的 我很忙 不过很高兴认识你 Paul
Really,I'm very busy.Nice to meet you though,Paul.
这样吧 不如现在就去瞧瞧
I tell you what.Why don't you swing over now?
看看新的办公室 顺便跟Golden Balls打个招呼
Check out the new offices?You can say hello to Golden Balls while you're there.
- 好啊 没问题 - 太棒了
- Yeah,all right. - Great.
我打电话给我的秘书 说我正在路上
I'll just ring my secretary,tell her I'm on my way.
- Dorothy - Dorothy?
- Dorothy. - Dorothy?
不行
No.
- 我们还没准备好 明天才行 - 不然就没机会了
- We're not set up.We said tomorrow. - I was losing him....
- 我们现在就出发 - Danny 时间不够啊
- We have to go now. - Danny!There's not enough time.
Dorothy 听得见吗?
Dorothy.Can you hear me?
- 电话线路非常.... - Danny
-The line's very.... - Danny.
好的 我们走
Okay,let's go.
对不起 有什么事?
Excuse me.Can I help you?
亲爱的 别诱惑我
Don't tempt me,darling.
我们来给二楼做个检查
We've come to give the second floor a once over.
我以为你们明天才开始
I thought you weren't starting till tomorrow.
明天?听着
Tomorrow?Look.
你做过粉刷装修工作吗 甜心?
You ever done any painting and decorating,sweetheart?
- 一点点 - 那么 你有没有听过"提前检验"?
- A bit. - Right,you ever heard of prepping?
- 我.... - 我的天!
- Well,I.... - God bless.
那么这样 你和我们一起上楼....
I tell you what,you can come upstairs with us...
我们大家可以互相帮助
and give us both a hand,if you like.
- 我打赌 你穿工作服一定很棒 - 我想 你们自己能搞定
- I bet you'd look great in a pair of overalls. - I'm sure you'll manage.
我带来的 不接任何电话 谢谢
He's with me.Hold all my calls.Thank you.
就是这儿 头儿都在这一层 那么...
Right,this is the boss's floor,more or less...
这是他的办公室
and here's his office.
- 你迟到了 - 抱歉 工作午餐耽误了
- You're late. - Yeah,sorry,business lunch.
- 我带了个人来 - 哦?谁啊?
- I brought someone back with me. - Yeah,who?
这个是我的老板Martin Stuart Martin 这是...
This is my boss Martin Stuart.Martin this is....
Howard Jennings
Howard Jennings.
哦 你就是Jennings?
So,you're Jennings?
你听说过我?
You've heard of me,then?
James Harrison 10分钟内到 我们得用到他的分析报告
James Harrison is due here in 10 minutes,we'll need his portfolio.
好的 我去找出来 行吧?
Well,I'll go and dig it out then,shall I?
自从我来这里 听到的都是关于你的事
You're about all I have heard since I've been down here.
因为这是我的城市
That's because this is my city.
我了解这里的每一寸土地
There's not a patch of undeveloped land in London that I don't know about...
也领受了第一次失败
and have first refusal on.
如果是真的 那我很快就要失业了
If that's true,I guess I'll be out of a job soon.
显然是
You said it.
那就是你想来告诉我的?
Is that what you've come to tell me?
还不止这些
Pretty much.
事实上 我怀疑我们是不是竞争对手
Actually,I doubt we're in competition.
你买卖土地 我也是
You buy and sell land,so do I.
没错 不过我的买卖更专业
Yes,but mine's more specialized.
专业?
Specialized?
如果你不介意 我还有其他事要做
So if you'll excuse me,I do have some work to be getting on with.
我让Paul带你出去
I'll get Paul to show you out.
我要Harrison的文件 马上!
...Harrison's file on my desk now.
带Jennings出去
Show Jennings out.
Howard
Howard.
- 很高兴认识你 - 是的 下次记得先预约
- Well,it was a pleasure meeting you. - Yeah,next time make an appointment.
你该感到惭愧
You should be ashamed of yourself.
事情还顺利吗?
How did it go?
轻而易举
It was a piece of cake.
- 我们都还没布置好 - 什么?
- We weren't even set up. - What?
- 他把他直接带来了 - 我看有机会 就把握住了
- He brought the mark back with him. - I had a chance and I grabbed it.
如果我们没时间准备怎么办?
What if we couldn't have got set up in time?
Mickey 我对你有信心 不是嘛?
Mickey,I had faith in you,didn't I?
- 你的袜子呢? - 这里有一只
- Where're your socks? - Here's one of them.
抱歉 Danny 不过 这看起来有点混乱
Sorry,Danny,but it does seem a bit messy.
混乱?
Messy?
通常我们都事先计算好 一个完整的计划
Usually we have it all worked out.You know,a proper plan.
听着 伙计 听我说 我们有计划 是的 我们有计划
Listen,gang.Listen up.We have got a plan.Okay,we've got a plan.
全在这儿
All up here.
你难道不知道那有多危险?
You've no idea how frightening that is,have you?
相信我 行不行?
You just got to trust me,haven't you?
那么下一步是什么?
What next,then?
是啊 我正在做呢
Well,I'm working on that one.
目标会做的第一件事是什么?
What's the first thing the mark would do?
呃 他会....
Well,he'd....
你该怎么做?
What would you do?
好的 别提醒我
Right.Don't tell me.
都听到你脑袋里吱吱作响的声音了
You can almost hear the cogs turning.
查找Cityrise Ash 麻烦建个网站
Research Cityrise.Ash,please set up a web site.
我正打算要说 我正想说
I was just about to say that.
Ash 做一下搜索的东西
Ash,go and search the thing.
我正准备要说呢 Mickey
I was just about to say that,Mickey.
好的 各位都听好了 明天...
All right,troops,everyone listen up.Tomorrow.
Ash 把场地搞定
Ash,get the yard ready.
Stacie 我要你去博物馆 Albert 你要成为黄金鉴定专家
Stacie,I want you down the museum.Albert,you're our gold expert.
- Mickey 你去一趟银行 - 干什么?
- Mickey,get yourself off to the bank. - What for?
取50便士出来
Get your 50p out.
有没有觉得 我们创造了个怪物?
Do you ever have the feeling we've created a monster?
一直都这么认为
All the time.
好的 还有多远?
Right.How far away?
很经典的作品 是不是?
Remarkable examples,aren't they?
你在这工作?
Do you work here?
我主要研究铜器时代
I'm in charge of the Bronze Age.
不仅仅是铜器时代 我是指 同一个时期的
Well,not the Bronze Age as such,I mean,that's a period of time.
那让我感觉象个女王 穿梭在时空中
That would make me a queen,and a time traveler,at that.
事实上 我负责研究该时期的出土文物
No,I'm actually in charge of the artifacts that hail from the period.
这些是我最引以为傲的
And these are my crowning glory.
伦敦最为神秘的文物之一
One of the great mysteries of London.
也许会有些荒诞 据说伦敦某个地方有金矿
It seems a bit far-fetched,that there's a gold mine in London somewhere.
不 并不奇怪
No,not really.
毕竟 六千年以前 地表构造和现在完全不同
The landscape was very different 6,000 years ago,after all.
不过 也存在可能性
No,it's perfectly feasible.
而且 我们博物馆有个地质学专家
In actual fact,we have a professor of geology here in the museum...
他正在撰写相关的论文
who's writing a paper on it.
是吗?我怎么才能找到他?
Really?Where do I find this professor?
我是个慈善家 专门投资科学研究
I'm a philanthropist,I invest in scientific studies.
是嘛 我想他会很高兴见到你的
In that case,I'm sure he'd be happy to talk to you.
我把他的号码写给你
Let me write down his number.
据说 这个原始的矿藏将价值上百万
It says here the original mine would be worth millions.
没错
Indeed.
我估计 这里所展示的 只是实际的1%吧
I doubt what you see here represents even 1% of what was actually there.
当然 出产地也许已经建了高楼大厦...
Of course,the site has almost certainly been built on by now,so...
谁知道呢 是不是?
we'll never know,will we?
我在另一面写了我的号码
I've written my number on the other side.
好好欣赏 玩得愉快
Enjoy the rest of your visit.
Saxon village的复制品也很经典
The Saxon village reconstruction is excellent.
你觉得Danny搞不定这事 是不是?
You don't think Danny's going to pull this off,do you?
是的
No.
可是 你还是让他尝试了?
But you're letting him try anyway?
他觉得我们做的事都很容易 让他受点挫折没坏处
He thinks what we do is easy.Won't hurt to bring him down a peg or two.
顺便赌赢这场比赛?
And win the bet in the process?
为胜利者干杯!
To the victor the spoils.
喂?
Hello?
根据我的笔记 Howard....可以叫你Howard吗?
According to my notes,Howard....May I call you Howard?
当然
Yes.
普遍观点认为 大部分金矿的形成...
It's widely believed that most gold deposits,particularly...
尤其是火山岩和沉积岩的那种矿山...
of the volcanic and sedimentary variety...
是由于岩浆带动地下水
were formed from circulating ground waters...
循环而形成的
driven up by magma.
不过 当然 也可能是 岩浆冷却后形成的
But,of course,it could also be expelled from the magma itself as it cooled.
- 所以 伦敦也可能出现这种情况? - 哦 是的
- And this could happen in London,right? - Oh,yes.
没理由怀疑 尽管专业得来讲...
No reason not,although geologically speaking...
- 条件并不十分理想 - 但还是有可能的?
- conditions aren't ideal. - But is it possible?
哦 是的 还是有不少残留物质
Oh,yes,there are certain residues...
经过了数千年历史的洗涤
that have been around for thousands of years.
如果你认为地里有黄金 你怎么来确定呢?
And how could you find out if you thought you had land with gold in it?
很多办法 总之需要做个土壤测试
A multitude of ways,mostly by a simple soil test.
土壤测试?
Soil test?
我可以带些土壤给你
So I could bring you some soil...
你可以告诉我 地底下是否有黄金?
and you could tell from that whether there was gold underground?
不行 我得做很多其他实验
No,I have to have further tests for that.
但是我可以判断出可能性
But I could determine that the possibility was there.
准确率呢?
How accurately?
得视地表层的面积而定
It depends on the size of the deposit.
大概百分之八,九十吧
80,90%,possibly.
你有这样一块土地?
You hold such a piece of land?
不 还没有
No,not yet.
不过 如果我有的话 你可以为我做这个测试吗?
But if I did,would you be prepared to do this test for me?
当然可以 如果博物馆不反对的话
Yes,of course.If the Museum has no objection...
我很乐意帮忙
I'd be happy to help.
你说什么?我不需要这个 我不需要
What you talking about?I don't need all this.I don't need all this.
是的
Yes.
就这么做 好吧 就这样
Just do it,all right,do it.
她很可爱 是不是?伙计 你好 什么事?
Cute,isn't it?All right,mate,how you doing?What's up?
其实 Nick还不知道这件事 他就要离开我们了
Basically,Nick doesn't know it yet,but he's leaving us.
所以的他的工作暂时无人接替 也许你对这个职位会有兴趣
So his job's up for grabs.I just thought you might be interested.
年薪5万 加上佣金就翻倍
50K a year,double that with your commission...
汽车 住房津贴
nice car,relocation allowance.
真不错 我在听
Lovely.Yeah,I am listening.
只是我不知道 你是否适合这个位置
Only trouble is I'm just not sure you're right for it.
我也不知道 我是否想为你工作
I'm not sure I want to work for you.
别生气 Paul
Don't take offense,Paul.
我想知道 你曾经做过些什么项目?
It's more about what kind of deals you're used to handling.
我是说 和Martin一起 你做过最大的项目是什么?
I mean,with Martin,what's the biggest deal you're doing?
我是不是象个木偶?
Do I look like a Muppet?
- 什么? - 你想打听我们的客户
- Pardon? - You're just trying to nick all our clients.
好吧 算了
All right,well.
只是随便打听下 不用那么认真吧
You can't blame a chap for trying,can you?
好吧 就谈谈其中一个项目
Okay,look,just talk me through one of your deals.
我想说...
I mean....
Martin曾经谈到过的 是什么呢?
Martin was talking about one the other day.What was it?
Jubilee的案子?
The Jubilee deal?
- 你知道那个? - 一点点而已 那是什么?
- You know about that? - A little.So what is it?
我只知道....
All I know...
我只知道 我们被要求出面购买一块土地
all I know,is that we've been hired to buy a parcel of land...
不管出多少价
regardless of price.
- 谁要求的? - 那我不清楚
- By who? - That I don't know.
Martin对这个很保密的
Martin's very secretive about it.
也就是说 就他一个人知道
Which usually means that he wants to take all the credit.
你知道是哪块土地吗?
Do you know where the land is?
据说拥有者是一个废品回收商
It's owned by an old rag and bone merchant.
我们出两倍的价钱 现金支付的 但是他始终都不同意
We've offered him twice what it's worth in cash,but he ain't having any of it.
用现金?
Cash?
是的 他不喜欢银行
Yes,he hates banks.
就是个废物
It's a shithole.
我不明白的就是...看那儿
That's what I don't get.I mean,look at it.
不过就是2间房子 不是嘛?
Barely going to get two houses in there,are you?
我承认 它离Jubilee线并不太远
I mean,it ain't that far from the Jubilee line,granted.
可我就不明白 老板为什么如此渴望得到它
But,I don't know,the boss seems very keen to pay way over the odds for it.
是啊 你能替我引见下主人吗?
Right,can you get me in to see the owner?
我有什么好处呢?
What's in it for me?
我们之前谈的那个职位
The job we discussed earlier.
不行
No.
听着
Look.
我不知道你想做什么
I don't know what you're up to,all right.
我不知道 我也不在乎
I don't know,I don't care.
可是 你突然告诉我这件事
But,you cut me in and then maybe,you know...
要知道...也许 我会当真的
maybe I'll suddenly start thinking about it.
我喜欢你 Paul 就好象看见了自己
I like you,Paul,you remind me of me.
所以?
So?
没错 成交了 你安排见面时间
Yeah,you've got yourself a deal.Set up a meeting.
我只知道 我们被要求出面购买一块土地
...all I know,is that we've been hired to buy a parcel of land...
不管出多少价
regardless of price.
...不管出多少价
...regardless of price.
- 让你想到了过去 是不是? - 什么?
- Got to you the other day,didn't it? - What?
- 去监狱探望Harry之后 - 是啊 是有点
- Going to see Harry in prison. - Yeah,a little.
不过 你已经惹麻烦了
In which case,you've got a problem.
你知道现在这事情很棘手 不是吗?
You know this is going to go pear shaped,don't you?
那孩子太操之过急了
The kid's gone off 100 miles an hour.
没有计划 没有诱饵 没有补救措施
Little or no groundwork,no convincer,no Plan B.
行了 要相信他 目前为止他做得很好
Come on,give him credit,he's played it well so far.
得了 Mick 你和我一样心知肚明
Come on,Mick.You know as well as I do.
筹备诈骗行动和能否顺利逃脱
There's a huge gulf between setting up a long con...
毕竟还是有很大区别的
and actually walking away clean.
我知道
I know.
就是说 你已经有决定了
Which means you've got a decision to make.
什么?
Which is?
如果他失手了 你会替他收拾烂摊子吗?
If it's going down the pan,do you bail him out?
还是让他从失败中吸取教训 顺便赢了这次的赌局?
Or do you let him fail,to teach him a lesson and win the bet?
即使那意味着 你要重新回去坐牢
Even if that means you going back to prison.
喂?
Hello.
Howard
Howard.
是的 这块地值21万
Yeah,the land's worth 210.
我想Martin的最后报价是42万
I think Martin's latest offer was 420.
是的 45万应该没问题
Yeah.450 should do it.
好的 什么时候?
Okay.What time?
好的 很好 我一会到
Yeah,that's fine,I'll be there.
好 一会见
All right,bye.
上钩了
We're on.
喂?
Hello?
Jennings先生 是的 你好
Mr.Jennings.Yes,hi.
十点半 在哪里?
At 10:30.And the address?
好的 我就来 再见
Right.I'll be there.Bye.
喂?Howard?好的 当然
Hello?Howard?Okay,sure.
没问题
No problem.
在哪儿?好的
And the address?Fine.
真奇怪
That's weird.
他为什么要所有的人都到场?
Why does he want everyone there?
我说过 不是嘛?他戒心很重
Well,I told you,didn't I?He's a control freak.
好吧 没问题
Okay.No problem.
Ash 去准备下
Ash.Go get set up.
准备好你的50便士吧
Better get your 50p ready.
- 准备好了? - 是的
- Right,you set? - Yeah.
再过10分钟
Okay,10 minutes.
看起来情况不妙
This doesn't feel good.
那是Danny的事
It's Danny's call.
Howard
Howard.
好啊
How are you?
我想最好还是带着保镖 这可是一大笔钱
Thought I'd better bring some security.There's a lot of money in here.
好啊 伙计 欢迎
All right,lads,welcome.
这个是Colin
Here he is,Colin.
这就是我跟你提过的Jennings先生
This is the man I was telling you about.Mr.Jennings.
这是Colin Nash
This is Colin Nash.
很高兴认识你 Nash先生
I'm pleased to meet you,Mr.Nash.
看上去 你象是准备打一场硬仗
You look like a man who's prepared to drive a hard bargain.
是啊
Yeah,rats.
- 是吗? - 我开门见山说
- Really? - I ain't got long.
这家伙很对我胃口
A man after my own heart.
他说 你的价比那个家伙要高
He tells me you're willing to beat the other bloke's offer.
没错 合同在这里
Indeed,yes,there's a contract here.
钱也在这里 都是现金
And the money's in here.In cash.
我明白你不喜欢银行
I understand you don't like banks.
是的 就象吸血虫
No,leeches.
我也这么认为
I couldn't agree more.
那么 你准备了多少钱?
So how much you got in there,then?
45万
450,000.
到时间了
It's time.
小心点
Be careful.
我们成交了?
So,do we have a deal?
当然 再做一件事就行
Absolutely.Just one condition.
我要做个土壤测试
That I carry out a soil test.
土壤测试?
Soil test?
是公司的规定
It's company policy.
非常感谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
- 我不知道 为什么我也得来 - 他们是谁?
- I'm not exactly sure why I'm here. - Who are they?
他们是来做测试的
They'll be carrying out the tests.
没有人说要做什么土壤测试
No one said nothing about no soil test.
不做测试 交易也取消
No soil test,no deal.
好吧 快点 就象我说的...
Yeah,well hurry up,then,like I said...
我没多少时间
I ain't got all day.
我把所有东西都带来了 不用多长时间
I've got everything I need here,it wouldn't take long.
你开始吧
In your own time.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你到底想找什么?
What exactly are you looking for?
你会知道的
You'll see.
是吗?你确定?
Well?Are you sure?
绝对是微量的黄金
Definite traces of gold.
我认为 地底下曾经有过一条地下河
It's my belief there was an underground stream here at some point...
是一条支流 并把一些物质带到了地表 瞧见了没?
skirting the main source and bringing the particles up to the surface.See?
太棒了
Excellent.
- 那么 成交了? - 基本没问题
- So do we have a deal? - It would seem so.
再做一件事就可以签约了
Just one more bridge to cross and then we can sign.
什么事?
What bridge?
行了
Okay.
Howard 如果你是在开玩笑 我就走了
Howard,if you're messing me about,I'll go.
事实上 Paul...
The thing is,Paul...
那让我感觉是个有预谋的诈骗
it occurred to me this might all be part of some elaborate con.
- 诈骗? - 是的 你可能听过那些骗取信任的把戏
- Con? - Surely you've heard of a confidence trick.
比如 你们这些人是一伙的?
For example,say you were all part of the same gang?
我怎么会知道?
How would I know?
一个星期前 我一个都没见过
I haven't met any of you until this week.
对于我来说 把一整箱的现金
So for me to part with a briefcase full of cash...
交给认识不到一个星期的人
to people I've known for less than a week...
是不是有点傻?
would be pretty stupid,wouldn't it?
而我 并不傻 所以...
And I'm not.Stupid,that is.
我想 最好还是多点保障
So I thought I'd better get some insurance.
你瞧 教授刚刚告诉我 这里可能有黄金
You see,the Professor has just told me there are gold deposits here.
黄金?
Gold?
没错 你老板对此不是很保密吗?
That's right,yes,your boss was very secretive,wasn't he?
尽管你知道土地在哪里 他出多少钱
Although you knew where the land was and how much he'd offered.
所以现在 我要再做个测试
So now I do my own tests.
在你们告诉我 地下有黄金的5分钟后
And if they don't find anything...
他们却找不到任何东西
five minutes after you've assured me there was gold...
那么我相信 你们是在诓我
then I'd have to assume you were about to con me.
一个都不准走
No one leave.
如果他们找不到黄金 我觉得他会发狂的
When they don't find gold,I've got a feeling he's going to be very pissed off.
如果你能告诉我 你打算从哪条路溜走
So if you tell me which way you're going to run...
我相信 我们溜的时候不至于撞在一起
I can make sure we don't bump into each other.
该死的
Shit.
- 我真希望Danny准备了B计划 - 或是C计划
- I really hope Danny's got a Plan B. - And C.
那是什么?
What's all this,then?
不会很久的
Won't take long.
- 是只害虫 - 你弄完了没?
- Vermin. - Are you quite finished?
得烧了它
Have to burn them.
嗨 这些血是什么回事?
Hey,what the bloody hell's all this?
我猜你也该现身了
Do you know I thought you might make an appearance.
Paul?
这是我的项目
This is my deal.
- 你知不知道你在干什么 - 听着
- You have no idea what you're doing. - Look.
Jennings先生出价比你高 对方也同意了
Mr.Jennings has topped your offer,it's been accepted.
没你的事了
Get over it.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
我想 你只是正巧路过吧?
You just happened to be passing,I take it?
不 我不是路过 Dorothy 告诉我 他在这里
No.I wasn't just passing.Dorothy told me he was here.
我们已经成交了
We've done the deal.
我是来重新开价的
I'm here to make another offer.
Nash先生 我新报一个价 希望你能考虑
Mr.Nash,now,I have another offer that I really think you should consider.
老板
Boss.
得了
Okay.
我们搞砸了
We're screwed.
我就知道 他会让Albert先做个测试
I take it he got Albert to do a test first.
你怎么会知道?
How did you know that?
这是唯一的方法 确信他是不是被骗了
That's the only way he'll know for certain if it's a con.
那么我们该怎么做?
So what are we going to do?
Nash先生 我们成交了
Looks like you've got yourself a deal,Mr.Nash.
在这签个名
If you could sign there.
非常感谢 Nash先生
Thank you very much,Mr.Nash.
看上去 你大为恼火啊 Golden Balls
Looks like you've been pipped at the post,Golden Balls.
很抱歉 多做了些事 没办法 就怕错信了人
Sorry about all that other stuff,but you never know who to trust.
Paul 关于那个工作 我还是决定留着Nick
Paul,about the job.I've decided to keep Nick on after all.
抱歉
Sorry.
有没有人告诉我 到底怎么回事?
Can someone explain to me what just happened?
- 他找到了黄金 - 怎么可能?
- He found gold. - How?
我猜 Jubilee遗址就在这附近
Well I guess the Jubilee site had to be somewhere.
那就是说 这块地价值上百万
But that means this place could be worth millions...
我们用45万就把它卖了?
and we just flogged it to him for a poxy 450K.
有得必有失嘛
You win some,you lose some.
真够惊险的
That was intense.
快点离开这里
Let's get out of here.
我还是没明白
I just still don't get it.
本该是件非常糟糕的事 不过...
It would have been a terrible,terrible thing.But....
真是奇妙啊
Strangely....
我美妙的生活 差点毁于一旦
My sex life would have been a terrible thing.
我还真是不太习惯
Do you know I could get used to this.
一个安静的Danny
A quiet Danny.
沉默是金
Silence is golden.
笑得很开心嘛
Having a good laugh,are you?
大家都笑那么开心
Everybody having a good laugh?
好吧 我的50便士呢?我还要一封信
Okay,where's my 50p?And I want a letter.
- 一封信? - 是的 要你亲笔签名
- A letter? - Yes,I want a letter signed by you...
为低估我的能力 和不公平的待遇而道歉
apologizing for underestimating me and stating uncategorically...
我是个更棒的诈骗专家 你们都亲眼见到了
that I'm the better grifter.You lot can witness it.
Eddie 拿些纸来 谢谢
Eddie,paper on the bar,squire.Thank you.
我希望能这么做 Danny 如果你真的赢了的话
I'd happily do that,Danny.If you'd won the bet.
- 我们是不是卖出土地了? - 是的
- Did we sell the land or not? - Yes.
- 好的 钱有没有拿到手? - 是的
- Yeah,is the money in the case or not? - Yes.
好的 那么付钱吧
Yeah,then pay up.
不 我们赌的是 那种诈骗方法最好
No,but the bet was which is the best style...
是你那种无组织 无纪律 走一步算一步
your unstructured,undisciplined,fly-by-the-seat-of-your-pants...
差点害大家都坐牢的诈骗方法呢
let's-all-go-to-jail madness masquerading as a long con...
还是我这种专业的 有计划的 各方面都考虑到 不会被逮到的诈骗方法
or my professional,reasoned,covering- all-the-angles,never-get-caught style.
废话
Bollocks.
- 那就是你的理由吗? - 不是 我的理由是 我们成功了
- And that's your argument,is it? - No,my argument is the con worked...
- 所以你得认输付钱 - 可是这个计划差点失败了
- and you should pay up. - But the con was falling apart.
我们还是拿到钱了
We still got paid.
那是因为 我帮了你一把
But only because I was watching your back.
- 什么? - 告诉他 Ash
- What? - Tell him Ash.
不 别叫我做这个
No,you leave me out of this.
你没有考虑到各个方面 所以我替你考虑了
You hadn't covered all the angles,so I had to do it for you.
你怎么做的?我都没听你提过
How did you do that?I didn't hear you say a word.
我不需要说什么
I didn't have to.
- 还记得Ash开的那一枪吗? - 是啊
- You remember Ash firing his gun? - Yeah.
他并没有打中什么
He didn't actually shoot anything.
- 哦 难道那只老鼠死于心脏病? - 事实上...
- All right,so the rat died of a heart attack. - Actually...
那是我事先准备好的
it was one I prepared earlier.
- 什么意思? - 他只是对着地上开枪
- What do you mean? - He simply fired into the ground.
为什么?
Why?
因为他在子弹里加了些黄金
Because he'd filled the cartridges with gold.
他的目标就是看中 他们取土壤样品的地方
All he had to do was aim at the spot where the sample was about to be taken...
然后开火 把黄金射入土壤里
and fire,peppering the soil with gold.
- 所以 地里没有黄金? - 当然没有
- So there weren't any gold? - No.
只有我们放进去的那些
Only what we put there.
哦 不 是为了替你收拾烂摊子而放的
Sorry,only what I put there to cover your ass.
经验加科学 Danny
Experience,science,Danny.
考虑到所有的方面
Covering all the angles.
而不是随心所欲
Not going off half-cocked.
所以 我赢了
So I win the bet.
是的 好吧....
Yeah,well....
不过...
Whatever.
算是打平了 怎么样?
Call it a draw,all right?
不 等一下....
No,now wait a minute...
如果我撒手不管 事情就麻烦了
if I hadn't bailed you out,the whole thing would have gone pear shaped.
如果不是我 我们一开始就不会做了
If it weren't for me,we wouldn't have been there in the first place.
- 你欠我50便士 付钱吧 - 不 该你付
- You owe me 50p.Pay up. - No,no you pay up.
- 可是我赢了 - 没有 你没赢
- But I won. - No,you didn't win.
你没赢 因为我 我们赢了一箱子钱
You didn't win.We made a case full of money because of me.
是我 因为我才赢了钱
No,because of me,you mean.
- 那个网站怎么说? - 我正打算做
- What about the web site? - I was going to do that.
我让Albert给你上一堂cold reading课呢?
I arranged for Albert to give you a lesson in cold reading.
什么 cold reading课?我早就知道那些了
What,cold reading?I knew that stuff already.
不 你并不知道
No,you did not.
看上去得吵一晚上了
Looks like it's going to be a long night.
没错 就让他们吵去吧
Yes,shall we leave them to it?
为什么就不承认 我光明正大了赢了你?
Why don't you just admit it,I beat you fair and square?
那你又为什么不肯承认呢?
Why don't you just admit it,all right?
我赢了那箱钱 你就得离开了
You were going to walk away,I made us a case full of money.
- 我讨厌不服输的人 - 是嘛?是嘛?
- I do hate sore losers. - Do you?
再赌一次
Double or quits.
- 什么? - 我想到一个好办法
- What? - I've got this great idea.
- 哦 不 - 不 听我说 鸽子
- Oh,no. - No,bear with me.Pigeons.
- 鸽子? - 是的 赛鸽
- Pigeons? - Pigeons,yeah.
塞鸽 我看到过这个 值很多钱
Pigeons.I read all about them.They're worth a fortune.
你会画鸽子吗?
Can you paint a pigeon?
- 不知道你在说什么 - 是因为你知道 我说对了
- I'm not even listening. - No.'Cause you know I'm right.
闭嘴 Danny
Shut up,Danny.